RESUME	

Name : Vetrivel Mahendran

EDUCATION

Title of the Degree with Branch	College/University	Year of Passing
BACHELOR DEGREE	Syed Ammal Engineering college/	2004
	Madurai kamaraj University	
XII	KVS Matriculation hr sec school	2000
X	KVS Matriculation hr sec school	1998

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Hardware	Desktop, iPad, iPhone and Android Devices
Operating System	Windows
Programming Languages	HTML 4/5, CSS 2/3, JavaScript, JQuery, JSON, PHP, Ajax, jQuery Mobile, Knockout JS, React JS, Angular JS, Redux, SASS and Bootstrap.
Databases & Tools	MySQL, Adobe Dreamweaver, Edit Plus, Tortoise SVN,GIT
Other Utilities	Notepad ++, Adobe CQ5, CRXDE
Location	Parsippany, New jersey / Chennai.

SUMMARY:

Associate has 13+ years of experience in the Information Technology. As part of his assignments, Associate has been extensively worked on HTML5, SASS, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Knockout JS, React JS, Angular JS, JSON, Ajax, JQuery Mobile and CMS like Smarty and Drupal also involved in integration, development of interactive web applications. Taken Leadership to handle various projects for the clients like Wyndham Destination Network (Formerly Group RCI), Pearson, Northwestern Mutual, Anthem, Aetna, IR, Allegion, Optus, Lordabbett, Homedepot and Vysr. My expertise lies in Web Development; Project planning, Execution and Delivery.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

Name of the Company	Designatio n	Address of the employer	From	То	Duration(Years)
Cognizant Technology Solutions India Pvt Ltd	Technology Specialist	Techno Campus, 5/535, OMR, Okkiyam, Thoraipakkam, Chennai - 600097	July 2014	Till Date	4.10 years
Sapient	Senior Interactive developer	Sapient Consulting limited, 5 th & 6 th Floor, Vayu Block,Salarpuria GR tech park,Whitefield Road, Bangalore -560066	January 2014	June 2014	0.5 years

MindTree	Technical Lead	MindTree limited,10 th Floor, TRIL Infopark ltd, Ramanujan IT City (OMR) Chennai-600113	April 2013	January 2014	0.9 years
Hewlett Packard	Technology Consultant	Hewlett Packard Global soft pvt.ltd, Citius A, Olympia Technology Park, Guindy, Chennai-600032	November 2010	March 2013	2.5 years
Photon Infotech	Software Engineer	3rd Cross St, Gandhi Nagar, Adyar, Chennai, Tamil Nadu 600020	August 2007	September 2010	3 years
Marlabs	Software Engineer	Marlabs Software (p) ltd, #54, Bowring Towers, Shivajinagar, Bangalore - 560001	May 2007	August 2007	0.4 years
OpenSols	Software Developer	OpenSols Infotech pvt ltd, 2nd Floor, 21St Main Road, Banashankari 2nd Stage, Bangalore - 560070	July 2006	March 2007	0.8 years
DCI	Web Programmer	Dot Com Infoway Pvt Ltd, Plot No:3, Vaigai Colony, 2 nd Floor, Anna Nagar, Madurai -625020	August 2005	May 2006	0.10 years

PROJECT PROFILE:

Project Title	Wyndham Destination Network -RCI
Duration	07/09/2018 – Till Now
Location	Parsippany New Jersey / Carmel Indiana
Hardware	Desktop
Operating Systems	Windows
Programming Languages	HTML 5, CSS 3, JQuery, JavaScript and
	RWD.

PROJECT DESCRIPTION:

RCI online, is a web application which is used for exchange their vacation with timeshare concepts. RCI has two programs as RCI week's programs and RCI points programs. RCI web application is developed using HTML 5, CSS 3 and JQuery with Responsive web design.

CLIENT DESCRIPTION:

RCI stands for Resorts Condominiums International. RCI will give a platform to exchange their vacation. RCI is a timeshare exchange company with affiliated resorts in 110 countries.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

He had involved in the development of responsive web pages using HTML5 and CSS3. He created various reusable component using JQuery. He participated actively in

requirements' gathering and getting the business logic. He involved in Agile Scrum Process and completing the Scrum tasks in allotted deadline.

DURATION OF THE PROJECT: 4 Months

PROJECT PROFILE:

Project Title	Pearson - Bowerbird
Duration	07/28/2017 - 04/06/2018
Location	Chennai
Hardware	Desktop
Operating Systems	Windows
Programming Languages	HTML 5 , CSS 3 , React JS, Redux &
	Angular JS

PROJECT DESCRIPTION:

Bowerbird is an answer variant collecting application to help train IBM Watson on the possibilities of right answers for a particular question. It has 3 types of users namely admin, student and scorer. Admin approves/rejects the fresh users and also assigns the answer variants to the scorer to score. Student will be answering the questions presented to him and will be paid for his attempts. Scorer will evaluate the answers. Based on the score for each answer collected, Watson gets trained.

CLIENT DESCRIPTION:

Pearson Education is the leader in education publishing. The Pearson Bowerbird is an answer variant collecting application to help train IBM Watson on the possibilities of right answers for a particular question.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

He had involved in the development of responsive websites for answer variant collecting system using HTML5, CSS3, React JS, Redux and Angular JS. He participated actively in requirements' gathering and getting the business logic. He involved in Agile Scrum Process and completing the Scrum tasks in allotted deadline.

DURATION OF THE PROJECT: 8 Months

PROJECT PROFILE:

Project Title	Northwestern Mutual - EfactFinder
Duration	01/04/2017 - 06/30/2017
Location	Chennai
Hardware	Desktop
Operating Systems	Windows
Programming Languages	HTML 5 ,SASS , React JS, Redux

PROJECT DESCRIPTION:

EfactFinder is an application for financial representative which is used to collecting details (Personal, Assets, Income.etc.) of the client at initial stage using Ipad, Surface, desktop.

CLIENT DESCRIPTION:

The Northwestern Mutual is an American financial services mutual organization. The EfactFinder is an application for financial representative has been designed to provide you with fast and easy access to collecting details (Personal, Assets, Income. etc.) of the client at initial stage.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

He had involved in the development of responsive widgets using HTML5 and SASS. He created various reusable widgets using React JS. He participated actively in requirements' gathering and getting the business logic. He involved in Agile Scrum Process and completing the Scrum tasks in allotted deadline.

DURATION OF THE PROJECT: 6 Months

PROJECT PROFILE:

Project Title	Anthem –Broker Portal
Duration	06/15/2016 – 10/31/2016
Location	Chennai
Hardware	Desktop
Operating Systems	Windows
Programming Languages	HTML 5, CSS 3, React JS, Redux

PROJECT DESCRIPTION:

Anthem Inc. is an American health insurance company which includes the modules like Online Store to find various Medicare solution for customer over 65 years and Broker portal which allows the brokers to feed the data of the customers in the system. He had involved in the development of those modules which includes the form creation along with the required validations and rules to search a Medicare solution and to provide the User Interface for the brokers to enter the customer's data.

CLIENT DESCRIPTION:

Anthem is a trusted health insurance plan provider. The anthem OLS and Broker web sites has been designed to provide you with fast and easy access to the tools and information you need most.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

He had involved in the development of responsive and adaptive widgets using HTML5 and CSS3. He created various reusable widgets using React JS. He participated actively in requirements' gathering and getting the business logic. He involved in Agile Scrum Process and completing the Scrum tasks in allotted deadline.

DURATION OF THE PROJECT: 5 Months

PROJECT PROFILE:

Project Title	Aetna – Meritain
Duration	06/01/2015 - 06/14/2016
Location	Chennai
Hardware	Desktop, Tablet, iPad, iPhone and
	Android Devices
Operating Systems	Windows
Programming Languages	HTML 5, CSS 3, Jquery and Knockout
	JS

PROJECT DESCRIPTION:

Aetna – Meritain has 5 portals like Admin, Member, Employer, Provider and Producer Portals which delivers various services to the Health care. He had involved in Portals module development which includes developing Dashboard with Insurance Claim Details of a several users, Contact Us forms which allows the user to have a communication with the provider/employer/member, Submit Referrals which allows the Provider/member to submit Referrals of various clients.

CLIENT DESCRIPTION:

Meritain, an independent subsidiary of Aetna, they are advocates for healthier living. As one of the nation's largest administrators of health benefits, they offer the resources of a national carrier and the unmatched flexibility and service of an independent, local administrator. Their approach is to provide employers with cost-effective plan administration within a custom framework of variable networks, industry-leading products and services, and cost management strategies.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

He had participated actively in requirements' gathering and getting the business logic. He had involved in development of Responsive web pages for Admin/Member/Employer/Provider/Producer Portal using HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Bootstrap, JSON and Knockout Js and provided the technical guidance to the team.

DURATION OF THE PROJECT: 1 Year

PROJECT PROFILE:

Project Title	Chola – Sale Application
Duration	01/02/2015 – 05/29/2016
Location	Chennai
Hardware	Desktop, Tablet, iPad, iPhone and
	Android Devices
Operating Systems	Windows
Programming Languages	HTML5, CSS3, Json and Angular Js.

PROJECT DESCRIPTION:

Chola – Sale Application is finance website which has many models like vehicle finance, home loans, home equity loans, SME loans, investment advisory services, stock broking and a variety of other financial services.

CLIENT DESCRIPTION:

Cholamandalam Investment and Finance is financial services provider offering vehicle finance, home loans, home equity loans, SME loans, investment advisory services, stock broking and a variety of other financial services to customers.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

He had managing and coordinating UI related work across the team for Sales Stream vehicle finance in chola. Provided the technical guidance to Team. He had involved in developing the Sales vehicle finance Web Pages for Cholamandalam Finance using HTML5, CSS3, Json and Angular Js.

DURATION OF THE PROJECT: 5 Months

PROJECT PROFILE:

Project Title	IR – Trane/ AmericanStandard Air
Duration	07/14/2014 – 12/31/2014
Location	Chennai
Hardware	Desktop, Tablet, iPad, iPhone and
	Android Devices
Operating Systems	Windows
Programming Languages	HTML5, CSS3, Json and Angular Js.

PROJECT DESCRIPTION:

IR – Trane/ American Standard Air is the website for the find dealer and shop the products like air conditioners, air handlers, air compressor systems, tools, pumps, material handling systems and more.

CLIENT DESCRIPTION:

Ingersoll Rand's diverse and innovative products range from complete air compressor systems, tools, ARO pumps, material handling systems and more. Ingersoll Rand provides products, services and solutions that enhance our customers' energy efficiency, productivity and operations.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

He had involved in developing responsive web pages using HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, Json and JQuery which can adapt to the Adobe CQ5 CMS. Provided the technical guidance to the team. He had Co-ordinated with vertical team and had maintained Zero Schedule Variation and Zero Effort Variation for the project and delivered the project on time which leads to have client level Appreciation in the project.

DURATION OF THE PROJECT: 6 Months